A Guide to the Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1848-1999
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lind Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1848-1999
The Library of Virginia
42531
7.7 cubic feet
Bock, Linda Wilkinson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Virginia Heistand Jones of Charles City County, Virginia, 19 January 2006
Biographical Information
Linda Elizabeth Wilkinson was born 9 November 1907 in Surry County, Virginia, to William L. Wilkinson (1861-1957) and Letitia Sarah Deverell Wilkinson (1874-1960), and grew up in Charles City County, Virginia. Linda Wilkinson graduated from Longwood College and became an elementary school teacher. She married Frederic Stanley Bock, Jr., (1909-) 17 July 1933, and they had no children. Linda Wilkinson Bock served as assistant director of the Disability Determination for the Virginia Department of Rehabilitative Services. With her husband, she was active in the Westover Episcopal Church. Bock died 5 March 2005 in Richmond, Virginia, and was buried at Westover Church in Charles City County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1848-1999, of Linda Wilkinson Bock (1907-2005) of Charles City County and Richmond, Virginia, consisting of papers relating to the Linda and Frederic S. Bock (1909-); Bock and Wilkinson families; William L. Wilkinson (1861-1957); Reverend Charles Edward Stewart (1884-1965) and Eleanor May Deverell Stewart (1883-1971); Westover Church and the Episcopal Church in Virginia; and the history, politics, religious, and social life and customs of Charles City County, Surry County, and Virginia. The collection is organized into the following series: Series I: Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1937-1999. Series II: Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers. Series III: William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1955. Series IV: Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952. Series V: Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969. Series VI: Westover Church, 1934-1991. Series VII: Miscellaneous Religious Materials. Series VIII: Pamphlets, Magazines, etc.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Series I: Linda Wilkinson Bock Papers, 1937-1999. Series II: Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers. Series III: William L. Wilkinson Papers, 1861-1955. Series IV: Account Books, Diaries, Ledgers, 1856-1952. Series V: Stewart Family Papers, 1935-1969. Series VI: Westover Church, 1934-1991. Series VII: Miscellaneous Religious Materials. Series VIII: Pamphlets, Magazines, etc.
Contents List
- Linda W. Bock Papers, 1937-1999 (Box 1-2)
  Linda W. Bock Papers, 1937-1999, contain address books, autograph books, books, correspondence, diaries, newsletters, notebooks, notes, pamphlets, and receipts. Diaries, 1942 and 1954-1956, cover Bock's life in Florence, South Carolina, in 1942, and at Byrdwood in Charles City County, Virginia, from 1954 to 1956. Topics include family and personal news; social life and customs; religion, including Bock's family's attendance at Westover Church in Charles City County; World War II; national, state, and local politics, including local elections in Charles City County and the 1956 presidential election; Supreme Court ruling on segregation; Bock's getting a part-time job as a high school counselor; charity giving for 1955 and 1956; and the weather. Also includes bulletins, cards, clippings, and correspondence filed within the diaries. Papers also include an address book; an autograph book, 1937-1938, signed by Bock's seventh grade students at New Kent High School; book of poems and sayings entitled LEAVES OF GOLD given to Bock in 1972; correspondence, 1942 and 1974, to Bock containing family and personal news; newsletter, June 1958, for the Link-Belt Company and newsletter concerning travel allowances; notebook containing a division of personal property, possibly from Byrdwood, 1971, and daily meditations and notes, 1982-1999, of Bock; notes, n.d., for Bock's Westover Church prayer group; pamphlet offering plays for sale to high school drama clubs; and a receipt, 25 May 1962, for Frederic Bock.
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1942 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, cards, etc. from 1954 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1955 Bock diary (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Linda W. Bock Diary, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, cards, etc., from 1956 Bock Diary (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1942-1974, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Autograph Book, 1937-1938, 7th grade class, New Kent High School (Box 2)
  - Address Book (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 1971, 1982-1989, containing a division of property (1971) and daily meditations (1982-1989) (Box 2)
  - Leaves of Gold given to Linda Bock in 1972 (Box 2)
- Wilkinson-Bock Family Papers (Box 3)
  Wilkinson-Bock family papers consist of Bible records, newspaper clippings, photographs, and miscellaneous items. Bible records consist of records for the Wilkinson and Kimbrough families, and include information on the Bock, Bowman, Branch, Bumpass, Cosby, Deverell, Finney, Jones, Nixon, Stewart, and Thornton families. Clippings, 1916-1988 and no date, include articles on Charles City County and its history; historic houses along the James River, including Berkeley, Shirley, Upper Weyanoke, and Westover; Poplar Hall in Virginia Beach, Virginia; Westover Church in Charles City County; drives through Charles City County; Hanover County, Virginia; the Virginia Episcopal Church; Short Pump, Henrico County, Virginia; United States history; George E. Pickett (1825-1875); William L. Wilkinson; and Philip Lightfoot's dance competition with the devil. Photographs include members of the Wilkinson family, the Branch family, John S. Alvis (1835-1884), equipment and docks of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, and a Christmas party and a dinner possibly for C and O employees. Miscellaneous items include inscriptions, prayers, notes, and other papers copied or removed from various books.
  - Family Bible records, 1769-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1916-1988, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wilkinson family photographs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Railroad and railroad equipment photographs (Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dinner, Christmas party, and gathering photographs (probably Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad employees) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Items removed or copied from various books (Box 3, Folder 6)